<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://0.0.0.0:5000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://0.0.0.0:5000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-06-05T22:54:21-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:5000/</id><title type="html">Kevin Arifin</title><subtitle>Kevin Arifin's blog. My collection of articles and weekly newsletters
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">On Investing in People</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:5000/on-investing-in-people" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On Investing in People" /><published>2020-03-20T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-03-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:5000/on-investing-in-people</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:5000/on-investing-in-people">&lt;p&gt;Throughout a lot of my life, I always gravitated towards positions of teaching and mentorship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In high school, I spent a lot of my summers as a basketball camp coach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In college, I spent most of my non-academic time running a science and engineering mentorship organization and teaching computer science courses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even post-college as I started a full-time role at Citadel, I always volunteered to be an intern buddy or talk with college students considering a role at the firm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What drew me to the experiences was a sense of giving back. At every step of the way, I’ve had people shape my education, career, and life for the better. I had parents that helped me pay for school, gave me the freedom to make mistakes, and also kept me on the right track. I was fortunate to have friends a year or two older in school that pushed me to try computer science, which was something I enjoyed studying and also set me up for a good career out of school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People underrate how much value their experience can bring to people aspiring to be in their position. Much of the advice I received, like starting a four-year plan for classes, writing a strong resume, and preparing for interviews, was a short conversation with a friend or mentor but helped me a lot in my academic and professional career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But both finding and having access to these mentors is a lot of happenstance and circumstance. Not all kids are born into families that can afford to pay for school. Not everyone went to a high school with an alumni network to connect with as you pick a college, select your first classes, and pick a major. Not everyone finds a mentor at work to help them jumpstart their career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s what led me to work on a startup that’s making the platform to invest in human potential. I envision a world where you can leverage your potential to access both capital and mentorship to pursue your education, find a fulfilling career, or start your own company. It’s a world that drives investment to those that are underinvested and people can take bets on themselves and on the people they believe in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This world already kind of exists today in the venture capital world, but it’s heavily gated by signaling and location. Most of the top VCs are in the Bay Area, and they look for founders with a proven track record, work experience from top startups and companies, or the best academic acumen. But the model of investing in a company’s equity is what makes these VCs generous with their mentorship. From Paul Graham, one of the most famous VCs in Silicon Valley:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Investors are different—-not because they’re more generous spirited than other people, but because they get equity. Tell investors you’re going to start the next Google and they immediately perk up. They don’t default to skepticism, because they like risky bets. And they don’t feel like you’re trying to put yourself above them, because they hope to be drawn up with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When people can invest in other people, startup founder or not, it unlocks a world of mentors that want to share in your success. It takes the happenstance out of finding a mentor, because people are going to want to find the people they believe in and back them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what my co-founder &lt;a href=&quot;https://nickchua.me&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Nick&lt;/a&gt; and I are building at Edith Labs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find our landing page &lt;a href=&quot;https://edithlabs.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. We have an exciting project going live in the next couple weeks. If my story behind Edith Labs resonates with you and you would like to be a mentor, either financially invested in a student or not, don’t hesitate to reach out at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:kevin@edithlabs.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;kevin@edithlabs.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Throughout a lot of my life, I always gravitated towards positions of teaching and mentorship.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:5000/images/chicago.jpeg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">What the Andrew Yang Campaign Meant To Me</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:5000/thank-you-andrew-yang" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What the Andrew Yang Campaign Meant To Me" /><published>2020-02-11T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-02-11T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:5000/andrew-yang</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:5000/thank-you-andrew-yang">&lt;p&gt;When I first listened to Andrew Yang on an interview with Sam Harris back in October 2018, I knew he was my candidate. He instantly made me interested in the 2020 Presidential race, but above all, instantly felt like someone who could truly change this country for the better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The campaign started small. I still remember telling friends about Andrew Yang and getting crickets in response. But slowly he caught on. My brother and I bought “First 500” hats. My friend Wayne became an organizer for Oakland Yang Gang. My girlfriend Sarah donated to his campaign, sent me tweet after tweet about his campaign, and was heartbroken when he dropped out. People were listening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a period of time, where I listened to every single Andrew Yang interview out there. This was before he became too big and was just doing podcast interviews. Sam Harris interview. The big Joe Rogan interview. A conversation with Ben Shaprio. Andrew on the H3 podcast, on Kara Swisher, on the Asian America podcast, Eric Weinstein, Off the Pill (with Niga Higa!). If Andrew was speaking, I had to listen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believed in a lot in his policies, the big one being universal basic income, or the Freedom Dividend as he called it. It was such a simple idea, yet would solve a lot of the problems our society faces today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But continuing to listen to him talk, it went beyond policies. I once reflected on my all-time inspirations list. Elon Musk, Steve Jobs, Kobe Bryant. Andrew Yang skyrocketed up there. I never thought an Asian man running for president would be name-dropped on my list of inspirations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I never in my life thought I could run for President, but in a weird way, his campaign made me feel like I could do it (not that I would want to). There was something oddly empowering with the way he carried himself as a normal person, pursuing a goal against all odds, and standing up to the establishment with ideas backed by numbers and logic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So many of Andrew’s qualities are qualities that I aspire to have. I started modeling my public speaking after him. Just as I channel my inner Steph Curry when I shoot, when I speak I channel my inner Andrew Yang. The humanness, the emotion he would show on stage, the love he would share for his family, the entrepreneurial spirit and energy, the attentiveness he would bring to every conversation - those are all qualities I admire and aspire to emulate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our country needs Andrew Yang the human. Thank you Andrew for what you’ve started - this is just the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">When I first listened to Andrew Yang on an interview with Sam Harris back in October 2018, I knew he was my candidate. He instantly made me interested in the 2020 Presidential race, but above all, instantly felt like someone who could truly change this country for the better.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:5000/images/thank-you-andrew-yang/andrew-yang.jpeg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How Leverage Divides Us</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:5000/leverage" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How Leverage Divides Us" /><published>2020-02-08T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-02-08T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:5000/leverage</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:5000/leverage">&lt;p&gt;AngelList CEO Naval Ravikant talks about three types of leverage: labor, capital, and product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Labor leverage is people working for you.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Capital leverage is investing into markets, people, and resources to create more wealth.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Product leverage is building and using tools to automate tasks and give you superhuman abilities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s interesting is that each type of leverage has dominated different points in history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Labor leverage had been the dominant form of leverage for most of history. The most populous countries, like China, India, and the Ottoman Empire, were the most prosperous. Countries waged wars to grow their empire’s population and put more people to work. Even in the 19th and 20th century, the corporations that employed the most people were the most valuable. But convincing people to work for you either requires fear, a lot of money, or a mission that people believe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Capital leverage became dominant in the late 20th century, as people developed the concept of financial markets. If you already had a large sum of capital, you could invest it to create more capital. Capital leverage is easier to control than labor leverage because was more flexible and unlike people, you could put your capital to work wherever you wanted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 21st century brought the rise of product leverage. Unlike labor leverage which was hard to control and capital leverage which was hard to obtain initially, anyone could develop product leverage by learning to speak the language of the robot army of computers in the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This basically is the basis of Marc Andreeson’s idea of “software eating the world”. Because labor and capital are expensive in their own ways, developing product leverage is increasingly appealing as companies and people look to increase their bottom line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what has been happening in Davenport, Iowa, a city I recently spent a week in. Deere cut their workforce in half and Caterpillar closed all their factories there. This was also not a single occurrence. 4 million manufacturing jobs across the midwest were lost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 21st century has brought about a gradual redistribution of leverage across our country. The economic heart of the United States used to be populous midwest cities centered around manufacturing, but now everyone wants to do six things in six places. From Andrew Yang’s book &lt;em&gt;A War on Normal People&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Smart people… do one of six things in six places: finance, consulting, law, technology, medicine, or academia in New York, San Francisco, Boston, Chicago, Los Angeles, or Washington DC.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a divide between “big cities” and the rest of America because labor, capital, and products - the tools that give you leverage - are becoming increasingly concentrated in these select regions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because leverage allows you to produce outputs greater than the sum of the inputs, businesses can create wealth that is then passed down to the individuals that work there.  When labor was the primary form of leverage, a large number of people reaped small fractions of the benefits. This is what drove economic growth in the midwest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, product leverage unlocked higher gross margins by reducing the gross number of people that need to do the labor. With product leverage, you can run a billion dollar company with just 13 people (see Facebook acquisition of Instagram). Many of my friends working in tech or finance are on trajectories to manage large groups of people (labor leverage), save large portions of their salaries for retirement (capital leverage), and work at companies building products with high gross margins (product leverage). Working for high leverage businesses allowed individuals to become highly leveraged as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a leveraged individual, a dollar earned is fifty cents spent, fifty cents saved, and a promise for fifty cents in the future. You make more than you need and have career trajectories that further increase your leverage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is in stark contrast to unleveraged individuals. A dollar earned is a dollar spent, with little room for growth in the given career path. It’s hard to worry about the future when your life is focused on making it through the next day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;definite-optimism&quot;&gt;Definite Optimism&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Peter Thiel’s book Zero to One, he introduces two axes for thinking about the future: optimistic vs. pessimistic and definite vs. indefinite. Let’s define these axes.
Optimistic vs. Pessimistic: do you believe the future is going to be better or do you fear the future will be worse?
Definite vs. Indefinite: do you believe you can make plans to control the future or do you believe the future is out of your control?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/leverage/definite.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive img-container-center&quot; style=&quot;max-width:400px; margin-top: 5px; margin-bottom: 10px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s focus on two views of the future: definite optimist and indefinite pessimist. While Thiel’s chart indicates the present United States to be indefinite optimists, I believe the U.S. is divided into two groups based on how leveraged an individual is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leveraged individuals are definite optimists. It’s hard not be optimistic when you can invest capital into funds that grow 15% each year, iPhones get smaller bezels and faster processors every year, and companies continue to outcompete each other for engineering talent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unleveraged individuals are indefinite pessimists. When one unexpected medical bill, car repair, or traffic ticket could take you into bankruptcy, it’s hard not to be pessimistic about the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a conversation with a retired farmer from McCausland, Iowa. He told me of many of the challenges of being a farmer. Big agriculture bought up all of the farmland, contracted out work to the local people, and paid them based on the results of the harvest. A bad season was especially challenging for their family.  Regulators made it difficult for independent small farms to raise their own livestock, as they had to meet certain requirements to be sold on the market and have certified vets to inject them with hormones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What was striking to me though was his apathy towards the situation: “It doesn’t matter to me anymore. My son is a farmer though. He has to deal with it now.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was not a one time occurrence. Every individual I talked to in Iowa shared a level of apathy, political disaffection, and hopelessness to improving their situation. But it’s hard to improve the future if you don’t plan for it. And it’s hard to plan for it when you’re unleveraged and focusing on making it through the present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;network-effects&quot;&gt;Network Effects&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Nodes that are “ahead” get picked more often by the other nodes because they are ahead and thus offer the nodes choosing them less friction and more benefit. When this gets repeated many times, it systematically directs more resources to the nodes that already have relatively more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This excerpt is from an article on network effects by James Currier, a managing partner of seed-stage venture firm NFX. If it feels like the world is getting more divided, it’s because it is. When places full of leveraged individuals like big cites are perceived as “ahead”,  smart people work there, invest there, and build their products there, increasing their leverage even more. This is what I call the leveraged cycle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Big cities are building a larger and larger lever to lift the world, while the rest of the world is trying to lift the world with their bare hands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;rebuilding-leverage&quot;&gt;Rebuilding Leverage&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So where do we go from here? I believe it all starts with rebuilding leverage in these presently unleveraged towns. How do we get people, capital, and products to invest in the problems of these towns?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a real opportunity here, and it’s not too late to solve it. In the late Clay Christensen’s book &lt;em&gt;Innovator’s Dilemma&lt;/em&gt;, he talks about how startups operate on a different value network than incumbent companies. We can see this today as startups in San Francisco and New York are solving problems for these places: large-scale enterprise software, scooters and micro-transportation, and a suite of services for millennials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The people in towns like Davenport live in the problems of their situation. These markets are too small and too distant for incumbent firms to come up with the solutions to solve them, making them ripe for disruption through product leverage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But doing so requires rebuilding leverage starts by redistributing the value created by product leverage. The transition from labor leverage to product leverage led to resources being concentrated in a smaller population of people. A basic income to redistribute the gains of product leverage rebalances the leverage of the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a town like Davenport, a basic income of $1000 a month for every adult would be a $74 million dollar investment into the city. Giving people a slight bit of leverage shifts their mindset from indefinite pessimist to definite optimist, allowing you to plan for a brighter future.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">How a cycle of leverage is dividing our country and some thoughts about bringing our country together based on my experiences in Davenport, Iowa.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:5000/images/leverage/iowa.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">2019 Year in Review</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:5000/2019-year-in-review" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2019 Year in Review" /><published>2020-01-02T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-01-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:5000/2019-year-in-review</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:5000/2019-year-in-review">&lt;p&gt;A question college students often ask me is “Do you prefer school or work?”. I used to think the two experiences were incomparable, and in many aspects, they still are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;College has a critical density of ambitious people around the same age that facilitates meeting different people and spontaneous hangouts. There’s enough randomness that you’re often forced to make new friends and enough continuity that you develop lasting friendships post-college.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s difficult to replicate this environment in the real world. Work is routine. You’re generally around the same set of people on a day-to-day basis, everyone is spread across various neighborhoods and cities, and spontaneity is hard to come by. But with the routine of work, comes a regular chunk of free time from 6 until bedtime and two free weekend days that give you a lot of freedom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This freedom is what differentiates school and work. This freedom allowed me to read, study, build, and learn exactly what I wanted. No longer were there a set of classes, reading material, and exams to guide your learning. You are your own teacher, instructor, and evaluator. This is both empowering and daunting, but if you spend enough time constructing your personal curriculum, it can be much more rewarding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The process of creating a personal learning environment helped me grow a lot in 2019. I never thought I’d share my thoughts publicly online, send out a weekly newsletter, and meet random people I met online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I start 2020 and my 24th year of existence, I break down my progress I’ve made this year in my reading and writing, the impacts of data collection around my health, and what I’m looking forward to in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;reading&quot;&gt;Reading&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since 2012 (when I read a record 32 books!), I’ve been tracking the books I read each year. But from 2013 to 2018, I read on average 12 books a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made a lot more time to read in 2019, finishing 27 books, up from 13 in 2018. While number of books doesn’t correlate with learning and retaining knowledge, consistently reading has been essential to expose me to new perspectives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past year, I read many impactful books, but these are the 3 books that had the greatest impact on my life perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/atomic-habits.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive img-container-center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Atomic Habits&lt;/em&gt; was foundational for a lot of the improvement I experienced this year. Everyone wants to make improvements to their life, but James Clear provides both the mindset and simple action steps to make those improvements real.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clear’s idea of habit stacking (pairing habits you want to develop to habits you already have) helped me sprinkle in reading throughout my day. I habit-stacked reading to various activities I did already, like drinking my breakfast smoothie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Making the habit as simple as possible and just practicing showing up encouraged me to start a one minute daily meditation that I’ve grown to a three minute daily meditation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s an essential read if you’re trying to make changes heading into the new year. I wrote two posts focused on ideas from the book which you can find below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://kevinarifin.com/identity-challenge&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Identity Challenge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://kevinarifin.com/one-percent&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;One Percent Every Day&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/books/theres-no-plan-b-for-your-a-game.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive img-container-center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought I worked hard, but Bo Eason takes it to another level. Bo was a scrawny high school kid from the middle of nowhere turned NFL safety. He shares his framework in &lt;em&gt;There’s No Plan B for Your A Game&lt;/em&gt; to be the best in what you do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There really are no secrets. It all starts with a declaration of what you want to be the best in and then creating an environment without distractions that provides the necessary support from your friends and family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book provides a unique set of stories from Bo’s experience as an NFL athlete and speaker, including stories from Lauren Holiday (Jrue Holiday’s wife) and Jerry Rice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/books/zero-to-one.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive img-container-center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Zero to One&lt;/em&gt; is a book of condensed notes from Peter Thiel’s Stanford class on startups. Thiel describes how many ideas as repeating the ideas of the past (going from n to n+1), but truly new ideas go from 0 to 1, a fundamentally different and more difficult process. If you’re going from 0 to 1, you are betting on an important truth that most people probably disagree with you on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most powerful aspect of the book is the mindset of someone who want to go from 0 to 1. Thiel defines the term definite optimism as someone who believes they control the improvement of society. Startup founders are definite optimists conspiring to change world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;writing&quot;&gt;Writing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2019, I sent 34 newsletters and wrote 20 posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sending out my newsletter every Thursday felt like a capstone to the week, and it’s still crazy to me that I’ve sent out 34 of them. While not all of them were the highest quality, having an obligation to write and share my thoughts each week helped me keep up with reading books and articles and reflecting on my experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My writing fell off at the end of the year, but it’s something I want to do more of in 2020. This thread from &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/andrewchen/status/890076892698750976&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Andrew Chen&lt;/a&gt; gave me the inspiration I needed to push through and redevelop my writing habit. It was helpful to realize that my writing didn’t necessary have to be original ideas - they could just be backing up my agreement or disagreement through talking with others and my personal reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are my favorite posts from the year:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://kevinarifin.com/impactful-individuals&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Four Trends of Impactful Individuals&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading, writing, and being more active on Twitter exposed me to a lot of interesting perspectives from successful founders, VCs, and engineers. This post was the four trends shared by these individuals: reading, writing, doing work that is not work, and synthesizing ideas from different fields.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://kevinarifin.com/lessons-2019&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lessons from a Year of Work&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I reflected on my personal learnings one year after graduation: taking care of life stuff, leveraging and compounding myself, surrounding myself with people I aspire to be like online and in reality, and savoring my 20s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://kevinarifin.com/why-im-voting-for-andrew-yang&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why I’m Voting for Andrew Yang&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post is more than just about Andrew Yang’s run for president. It’s a review of the economic impacts of universal basic income, or the Freedom Dividend as Andrew Yang calls it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;health&quot;&gt;Health&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was my first full year tracking a lot of health aspects about my life. Sleep and weight/body fat have been my key performance indicators for my health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2019-year-in-review/sleep_start.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive img-third&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2019-year-in-review/sleep_mid.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive img-third&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2019-year-in-review/sleep_end.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive img-third&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sleep has always been a poor habit of mine. In college, I regularly woke up past noon and would stay up way past midnight. Measuring my sleep motivated me to both sleep more and sleep at a consistent time. The feedback helped me realize I needed at least 7 hours of sleep and having a consistent sleep cycle increased my productivity and happiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2019, I increased my asleep time by almost 40 minutes and also went to bed and woke up on a more regular cadence (though I fell off during the holiday).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While it’s tempting to stay up late to do extra work or spend, I’ve found that the irregularity it causes to your sleep cycle and the consequential tiredness is not worth the extra work time at night. I found setting a sleep time around midnight and a wake up time around 8:30 a.m. plus/minus one hour made it easy to have a more regular schedule across weekdays and weekends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2019-year-in-review/bodyfat.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive img-half&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2019-year-in-review/weight.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive img-half&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started the year near a record-low weight and body fat, and while I did gain a bit of weight, I maintained an active lifestyle with lots of walking, daily workouts, and basketball.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My Apple Watch purchase sparked some new motivation to maintain my active lifestyle. I haven’t missed closing my rings a single day, so hopefully I’ll continue that streak through this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe a healthy body is conducive of a productive mind. Prioritizing my health has been essential in increasing happiness and productivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;looking-forward-to-2020&quot;&gt;Looking Forward to 2020&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not one for New Year’s resolutions (as Sarah says, you should be trying to improve all year), but the new year is a good time to reflect and identify improvements for the next year. These are three areas of improvement and habits I want to build up in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reading notes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to read a book and forget what you learned about it. In a similar vein to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gatesnotes.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Bill Gates’s blog&lt;/a&gt;, I want to share my notes of every book I read this year. This complements well with my hope to write more this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Growing my newsletter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven’t been as active about publicizing my newsletter recently, but starting the newsletter has been an unexpected way with developing and maintaining relationships with people offline. The goal of growing my newsletter is not just a goal to grow the number of newsletter subscribers, but develop more of these online/offline relationships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Continue my meditation practice&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been fairly consistent about doing a morning meditation even though I fell off during the holidays. My goal is to maintain my meditation for the year and increase my meditation time from 3 to 10 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2019-favorites&quot;&gt;2019 Favorites&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Best Meal:&lt;/strong&gt; Wahaha in Bali&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Favorite Weekend:&lt;/strong&gt; Thanksgiving weekend with Sarah&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Favorite City:&lt;/strong&gt; Chicago&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Favorite Sports Moment:&lt;/strong&gt; Kawhi Leonard series buzzer-beater against the Sixers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Favorite Travel Experience&lt;/strong&gt;: Day trip exploring Ubud&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Favorite Artist:&lt;/strong&gt; Lauv&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Favorite Song:&lt;/strong&gt; im so tired… by Lauv (861 plays)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">My reflections on 2019 regarding my personal growth, health, reading, and writing, and what I look forward to in 2020.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:5000/images/2019-year-in-review/heavenly.jpeg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Digital Fitness On Demand</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:5000/digital-fitness" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Digital Fitness On Demand" /><published>2019-10-24T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-10-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:5000/digital-fitness</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:5000/digital-fitness">&lt;p&gt;Imagine a world where streaming services were fragmented by genre. You could only find animated children’s movies on Disney+, Netflix had all the horror movies, HBO was the king of comedy, and so on. But no one watches just one genre of movie - you’d have to juggle multiple subscription services. Coincidentally enough, this is kind of what’s happening as everyone gets into the streaming video on demand game, but at least a Netflix subscription can satisfy most of your digital entertainment needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This thought experiment describes the current state of digital fitness. Each company offers a specific “genre” of exercise - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.onepeloton.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Peloton&lt;/a&gt; for spin classes, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.glo.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Glo&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gaia.com/yoga/practices&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Gaia&lt;/a&gt; specializing in yoga, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tonal.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Tonal&lt;/a&gt; with cable-based strength workouts, and independent trainers offering workout videos and programs for their own niche.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fitness isn’t a result of just doing one kind of workout. A common complaint about working out is how boring doing the same types of exercises is week after week. Not only is doing a different type of exercise more fun, studies have shown that cross-training (doing different types of exercise) reduces the chances of injury.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another aspect of digital fitness is having access to a large library of trainers. Every individual can find the best trainer for them for any type of exercise. After trying out several instructors for Glo, I found an instructor I liked and have only done yoga classes with him. When watching workout videos online, I generally stick with athletes I trust like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/kevindlo/?hl=en&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Kevin D Lo&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thenx.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ThenX&lt;/a&gt;. Personal training is personal because each individual has a different set of fitness goals, so individuals gravitate towards the trainers they trust to help them achieve their respective goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With these insights into the digital fitness space, these are the problems with the existing ecosystem:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Too specific on the type of exercise.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Too broad on the selection of teachers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-marketplace-for-digital-fitness&quot;&gt;The Marketplace for Digital Fitness&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enter a marketplace for digital fitness. Instead of a subscription to a company like Peloton or Tonal, you can subscribe to individual coaches. Think the &lt;a href=&quot;https://substack.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Substack&lt;/a&gt; of digital fitness. (For those unfamiliar with Substack, they provide a platform for writers to create blogs and newsletters and monetize them through subscriptions.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One side of the digital fitness marketplace is the people creating digital fitness content. Let’s call them trainers. The other side of the marketplace is individuals interested in working out. Let’s call them athletes. This is how I envision the marketplace for digital fitness:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Any trainer can upload self-created fitness content. Examples include training videos such as a spin class or a weightlifting workout, books and workout guides, and motivational videos. They set a monthly subscription price to access their content.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Athletes can subscribe to set of trainers that help them reach their personal fitness goals. They pay a monthly subscription fee for access to each trainer’s content.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The platform provides services that make it easy to become a successful digital trainer. From assisting with content creation to helping with customer discovery, the marketplace lowers the barrier for entry to become a digital trainer. From an athlete perspective, the platform can leverage usage patterns to recommend and personalize a set of trainers to subscribe to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This marketplace solves the two problems of the digital fitness marketplace today. Athletes can diversify their workouts by subscribing to the set of trainers across many different types of exercise. In my personal case, I’d have access to the best weightlifting, calisthenics, spin, and yoga trainer that fits my tastes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A marketplace would attract the best trainers because their upside is unlimited compared to coaching exclusively for a company like Peloton.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peloton’s excellent spin instructors drive a lot of the recurring subscription profit, which amounted to $77.4 million for the fiscal year ending in June 2019. The average Peloton instructor makes about $300,000 and there are about 30 instructors, which means Peloton instructors shared in just about 12% of the subscription profits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Peloton definitely deserves to reap much of those profits by aggregating the demand of spin class enthusiasts, some of the best spin instructors could drive high subscriptions by themselves. Assuming that the marketplace takes a cut similar to marketplaces like Airbnb and Uber, a marketplace would allow trainers on the platform to capture 80% to 90% of the subscription revenue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best trainers would bring along their loyal following to the platform, who can now subscribe at a lower rate since they are just paying for the trainer they love. As the athlete base on the platform increases, the marketplace becomes an aggregator of digital fitness demand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This makes monetizing a passion for fitness possible for everyone. Just as Substack allows anyone to monetize a newsletter, this marketplace allows anyone to monetize their fitness passion. ThenX can upload their workouts to the marketplace instead of building out their on app, which is missing the network effects of the marketplace. Someone who recently underwent a body transformation and lost a lot of weight can share their workouts and exercises to the niche of people interested in weight loss and body transformation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The marketplace for digital fitness is also a highly scalable and profitable business as well. Let’s evaluate a digital fitness marketplace as a tech company using the criteria from &lt;a href=&quot;https://stratechery.com/2019/what-is-a-tech-company/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Stratechery’s Ben Thompson&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Software creates ecosystems:&lt;/strong&gt; A software marketplace creates an ecosystem of athletes and trainers.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Software has zero marginal costs:&lt;/strong&gt; The marketplace is like Peloton without the bikes. The services the marketplace provides are a zero marginal cost offering.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Software improves over time:&lt;/strong&gt; The platform constantly improves. For trainers, the platform can continue improving its offering of tools for content creation and distribution which lowers the barrier for entry to become a digital trainer. For both trainers and individuals who work out, the more data the platform has, the better the platform can connect trainers and individuals.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Software offers infinite leverage:&lt;/strong&gt; Any trainer can now reach the entire world, and every individual working out can find the right trainer to achieve their fitness goals, no matter what type of exercise.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Software enables zero transaction costs:&lt;/strong&gt; Trainers and individuals can make frictionless one-on-one transactions using the marketplace.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The marketplace for digital fitness checks all five boxes for being a tech company. The last mover in the digital fitness space is going to be the marketplace that aggregates the supply of digital fitness. The best trainers are going to be on this platform because it gives them superior distribution and direct connection with athletes everywhere. Athletes want to train with the best trainers for them, and everyone has their own fitness goals. The marketplace leverages the internet to find the trainer just for you, whenever you want, wherever you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Most of the individual trainers have separate apps, books, or product lines to try to monetize their passion. But this only makes the market even more fragmented . On top of a subscription to peloton and glo you’d pay for an app from thenx and a program from athleanx. That’s four different places where you have to manage a subscription, just to workout.



People have always shown a willingness to pay for their health. Peloton sells a 2000 dollar bike, Apple watches are hundreds of dollars, Fitbits used to be everywhere. Money is there waiting to be spent in the right place.

More importantly, fitness training is about the coach. By subscribing to Peloton or Tonal, you are subscribing to the whole library of teachers but in reality you probably stick with your favorite one. People subscribe to individual trainers all the time already like Kayla itsines or thenx but because of the fragmentation, only the select few can make a living off of being a digital trainer.



The solution is to build a marketplace for fitness coaches and workout people.

Nick regularly buys programs from AthleanX or works out watching videos of ThenX. I get workouts by watching Kevin D Lo’s workout videos and jotting down a list of his exercises. But wouldn’t it be better if I could walk through the workout with him?

The average peloton trainer makes between 250k and 300k. There are about 30 peloton trainers. 9 million dollars. 915 million in revenue FY ending June 2019. Trainers right now are just receiving 1% of the market.

Peloton stats
181.1 million in subscription revenue

The platform:

1. Like Substack or podcasting, providing baseline tools to prepare and stream workout videos.
2. Direct relationship between trainer and athlete. No third parties or companies; we just facilitate a relationship.


 --&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Imagine a world where streaming services were fragmented by genre. You could only find animated children’s movies on Disney+, Netflix had all the horror movies, HBO was the king of comedy, and so on. But no one watches just one genre of movie - you’d have to juggle multiple subscription services. Coincidentally enough, this is kind of what’s happening as everyone gets into the streaming video on demand game, but at least a Netflix subscription can satisfy most of your digital entertainment needs.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:5000/images/nycentral.jpeg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Future of Apple</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:5000/future-of-apple" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Future of Apple" /><published>2019-09-12T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-09-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:5000/apple</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:5000/future-of-apple">&lt;p&gt;It’s that time of year again when Apple releases a new iPhone. I’ve religiously tuned in to every Apple keynote over the last couple years, and this might have been the least interesting one I’ve watched.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hardware updates have gotten more mundane as phone technologically seems to have reached an asymptote, and clearly the overemphasis on camera technology indicates a lack of innovation in other areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple has always appealed to me because of its integrated ecosystem of software (notes, photos, and messages that sync seamlessly across all devices and Airplay to stream videos and music are my personal favorites), so the lack of hardware updates won’t deter me from sticking with Apple’s hardware, so long as Apple provides a technology ecosystem vastly superior to other companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, this speaks to the shrinking hardware moat and leveraging their hardware moat into a stronger software moat by pushing to services. Services has never really been &lt;a href=&quot;https://stratechery.com/2016/apples-organizational-crossroads/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Apple’s strength&lt;/a&gt;, but their vast pool of Apple fan boys and fan girls gives them a huge subscriber base to work with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s most interesting about this push to services is the transition from Apple as an innovator to Apple as a sustainer: sustain the iPhone as the leader in phone hardware and generate incremental revenue through services. There’s nothing wrong with that business model, and the market has rewarded the company (up about 3% since the event). This is the root of a lot of the criticism Apple has received prior to the event: Apple is no longer the innovator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple is going to remain relevant so long as the phone is the main means of interaction with the internet. While I’m not here to predict the next medium of interacting with the internet (glasses, contact lens, a brain machine interface, or something even crazier), it’s hard to imagine Apple going all-in on new technology that would destroy their key revenue driver (the iPhone) nor do they have any incentive to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;History tells us that innovation happens when an upstart changes the dimensions of the playing field by going all in on a new paradigm. IBM and their mainframes were left in the dust when Microsoft introduced PCs and operating systems. Apple leapfrogged Microsoft with mobile phones and again revolutionized our interaction with technology. But the future is going to be a small upstart that approaches their paradigm just as Apple approached the iPhone: all in.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">A reflection of Apple's yearly iPhone keynote titled *By Innovation Only*. Apple builds a great ecosystem of products, but we shouldn't expect innovation from Apple anymore. Where we should actually be expecting innovation to be coming from.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:5000/images/apple.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Unbundling of Business</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:5000/unbundle" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Unbundling of Business" /><published>2019-08-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-08-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:5000/unbundling-of-business</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:5000/unbundle">&lt;p&gt;When we talk about unbundling, we all think of unbundling the cable package. Instead of paying one cable company one fee for all the channels, we subscribe to different streaming video on demand services like Netflix and Hulu and watch what we want, when we want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the more interesting unbundling is happening in business. In the past, companies had to handle everything: customer relations, documents and contractual agreements, internal communications, single sign on. Now there’s a company that does each of these: Zendesk, Docusign, Slack, and Okta, among many others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This deconstruction of the company allows these smaller companies to focus specifically on solving a business problem 10x better than a company’s in-house solution. It makes more sense to pay Slack hundreds or thousands of dollars a month to handle internal communication rather than hire your own engineers to build and maintain an internal Slack. That’s the foundation of the SaaS business model, and the internet allows these companies providing specific business solutions to capitalize on these verticals at almost zero marginal cost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/companybundle.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive img-container-center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Companies used to have full divisions focused on these internal tasks like communication, video conferencing, email security, or single sign-on, but each of these pieces is now broken up into a full company. This leads to the unbundling and decentralization of the company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s call this the bifurcated company distribution, inspired by Alex Danco’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://alexdanco.com/2015/12/17/taylor-swift-ios-and-the-access-economy-why-the-normal-distribution-is-vanishing/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; on the bifurcation of our economy. The bifurcated company distribution means that there will be a few monolithic companies that synthesize a diverse ecosystem and capitalize on immense returns to scale and a long tail of smaller companies that provide the 10x solution to a small set of problems. In fact, this type of thing is already happening today. Take a look at the largest 100 stocks on NASDAQ by market cap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;head&gt;

    &lt;script src=&quot;https://d3js.org/d3.v5.min.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot; src=&quot;https://www.gstatic.com/charts/loader.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; href=&quot;/css/style.css&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;

        google.charts.load('current', {packages: ['corechart', 'bar']});
      google.charts.setOnLoadCallback(drawMarketCapChart);

      function drawMarketCapChart() {
        d3.csv('/data/companies.csv').then((data) =&gt; {
            data = data.slice(data.length-100, data.length);
            var dataTable = new google.visualization.DataTable();

            dataTable.addColumn('string', 'Symbol');
            dataTable.addColumn('number', 'Market Cap');

            data = data.map((d) =&gt; [d.Symbol, parseFloat(d.MarketCap)]);
            dataTable.addRows(data);

            var options = { legend: { position: &quot;none&quot; } };

            var materialChart = new google.charts.Bar(document.getElementById('chart_div'));
            materialChart.draw(dataTable, options);
        });
      }

      $(window).resize(function(){
        drawMarketCapChart();
      });

    &lt;/script&gt;
  &lt;/head&gt;
&lt;body&gt;

    &lt;div id=&quot;chart_div&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/body&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a collection of the super-large organizations: think Microsoft, Apple, Google, Facebook, Amazon. Everyone else is part of the long tail. But that long tail is huge. I left out 2,900 other companies from the chart, which would only accentuate the bifurcation of companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple makes iPhones, tablets, speakers, and watches, and tries to stay on the cutting edge of both hardware and software. This requires immense scale and integration across that scale to create a seamless ecosystem of products. Amazon is the everything store. It controls the end-to-end pipeline of sale to distribution for retail. It’s scale allows it to offer one-day shipping and cheaper products. Microsoft is the enterprise ecosystem, but the most contentious of the monoliths. Microsoft provides a suite of enterprise products like Windows, Teams, Outlook, and Azure, but can they do it better than company focused solely on that specific enterprise product?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This brings us to the long tail. Services companies ServiceNow, Okta, Zoom, and Zendesk make up this long tail, and they have been some of the best performing stocks this year. Each has a market cap well north of 5 billion dollars, and they employ between 1,000 and 6,000 individuals. In contrast, Apple employees 132,000 employees and has a nearly 1 trillion dollar market cap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Company’s will only get smaller and the bifurcated distribution of companies ever more pronounced. More startups will bite off parts of a business, like recruiting, legal, or bank transfers, until all that’s left is the core of the company. I’m not arguing this is a bad thing. This is a net positive for everyone who starts a business. People start businesses not to deal with legal overhead or building internal tools - they start companies to solve a unique problem they see with the world. The more they can focus their team’s attention on those problems, the more engaged everyone will be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, being in the long tail doesn’t mean you’ll be there forever. There will be the occasional black swan that moves from the long tail to becoming a monolith. But those aren’t the companies that bite off business problems and provide 10x better services. They are the ones that use existing business solutions to singularly focus on solving human problems. Potential black swans are Uber (if they figure out self-driving) or Tesla (if they deliver on a lot of their promises).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The unbundling of the business makes crazy ideas like these possible. Company’s can focus solely on their mission and outsource different aspects of what a business used to be to specialist companies. This is the future of the unbundled business, and we are just witnessing the start of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Counterintuitively, the greater the bifurcation of the company distribution in a particular industry, the higher likelihood of a black swan. Unbundling the business lowers the barrier for entry for individuals to tackle new problems like climate change, autonomous driving, or brain machine interfaces. Extreme bifurcation is the consequence of operating in a playing field where value creation is unbounded by physical limits. It's also what creates innovation: the off chance of an individual synthesizing a solution to the hard problems we face. --&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">How service companies are slowly breaking up the idea of a business. Introducing the idea of a bifurcated company distribution: a few monolithic companies built on powerful ecosystems and a long tail of smaller companies focused on their core competency.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:5000/images/lakechi.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">One Percent Every Day</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:5000/one-percent" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="One Percent Every Day" /><published>2019-07-24T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-07-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:5000/one-percent</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:5000/one-percent">&lt;h4 id=&quot;lets-start-with-a-story&quot;&gt;Let’s start with a story.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a chubby fourth grader, I had the profound realization that I couldn’t be overweight and play basketball. Inspired by the star players of the time from Kobe Bryant to Dirk Nowitzki, I had dreams of playing in the NBA just like every kid that picks up basketball. Unfortunately that fell short, but the work ethic that came with working toward my dream has stuck with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every day, fourth-grade Kevin, I would do 50 push-ups and 100 sit-ups. I would go to my parents’ room, turn on the game on that night and do my nightly routine. Those habits compounded. When I learned to do pull-ups, I set up a pull-up bar under my bedroom door and would do 10 pull-ups every time I walked out of my room. I would eventually go to the park and shoot hundreds of shots a day and do dribbling drills around the house as I watched basketball on TV (thank you Mom for letting me wreak havoc).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just as I discussed in my post &lt;a href=&quot;https://kevinarifin.com/identity-challenge&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Identity Challenge&lt;/a&gt;, I wanted my identity to be a basketball player and I defined a process around this identity. While the outcome fell short of my aspirations, I made the Varsity basketball team against all odds. Even though I was far from the best player, I continued to work hard and I still love playing and watching basketball to this day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Little did I know that fourth grade Kevin was building up the atomic habits James Clear talks about in his book. Another of his powerful insights in the book is the idea of getting 1 percent better every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all learn about compound interest in 8th grade math then proceed to forget about it until we are 20 and someone tells us to open a ROTH IRA because if you put in money now, compound interest will make it worth much more when you’re allowed to withdraw it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The same thing applies to people. If you get 1 percent better every day, by the end of the year you are 38 times better.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s just doing the small things every day. I try to grow a little bit every day. You won’t see the effects of your investments right away, but over time they pay off in unexpected ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The easiest way to do this is to come up with a concrete list of things that you can do every day to improve. While you may not do all of them every day, try to pick at least one, and if you’re struggling, the easiest one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s my list of 1 percent activities. I do at least one of these things every day, no matter how busy or tired I am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do something active.&lt;/strong&gt; From longer workouts like basketball, running, or strength training to small things like doing ab-rollers or pushups, I try to do something active every day. Keeping my body healthy is essential to keeping my mind sharp.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read a book.&lt;/strong&gt; I’ve been habit-stacking reading everywhere. While I drink my morning smoothie, while I go to the bathroom, before I go to bed, or while I’m in an Uber or train to go somewhere. I sneak reading in as much as possible. As an added bonus, it keeps me off less productive things on my phone like browsing sports websites or social media.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Write.&lt;/strong&gt; My weekly writing centers around my &lt;a href=&quot;/thought_bytes/0b00110111&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Thought Bytes&lt;/a&gt; newsletter and up to this point I’ve sent out more than 10 newsletters and written almost 20 blog posts. A lot of my writing never leaves the ideation stage though. I’ve found it extremely valuable to write down any random thoughts I have throughout the day in the Notes app, and occasionally look back to trigger my memory.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meditate&lt;/strong&gt;. This is a new one for me. I’m starting to meditate for a minute each day (and hopefully building up from there). Some of my favorite thinkers, including Yuval Noah Harari, Naval, Justin Kan, and Nassim Taleb, are all advocates of meditation. In a world where everyone and everything is fighting for your attention, practicing to control your attention seems like a valuable investment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other suggestions, I would love to hear from you. These 1 percent activities won’t be the same for everyone so it’s up to you to reflect on what matters to you and how you want to grow. But hopefully this gives you a starting point to start compounding yourself.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">How one percent improvements compound into meaningful change. Thinking about one percent activities that you can do on a daily basis.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:5000/images/reflection.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Lessons from a Year of Work</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:5000/lessons-2019" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lessons from a Year of Work" /><published>2019-07-17T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-07-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:5000/lessons-2019</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:5000/lessons-2019">&lt;p&gt;These are my reflections after about one year of working. These ideas may not work for everyone, but hopefully challenge you to think about what you’ve learned in the past year, no matter what stage of life you’re in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr class=&quot;post-hr&quot; /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;take-care-of-your-life-stuff&quot;&gt;Take care of your life stuff.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finding a place to live, insurance, finances, and health. If those things aren’t in line, you’re going to have trouble sleeping, be stressed at work, and spend all your free time dealing with those things. It may be annoying to file taxes early, read about your health insurance, or keep a diligent budget, but those are the things that need to be done to give you the freedom to do things that you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It cost me a couple hundred dollars because I didn’t understand my dental coverage and went to an HMO dentist instead of an in-network PPO dentist. Investing in making sure to do these things right will save you a lot of time, money, and stress in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking care of your health is also essential. I worked out a lot through high school and college, and I’ve maintained that habit through my first year of work. I can’t emphasize enough the benefits of working out. It’s improved my health, focus and confidence. I don’t meditate, but exercise acts as my meditation, giving me an hour or so to think about nothing and break the monotony of sitting and using my brain. While it may cost me an hour every day, I think the productivity gains help me maximize the remaining brain time I have in my day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr class=&quot;post-hr&quot; /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;do-things-that-leverage-and-compound-yourself&quot;&gt;Do things that leverage and compound yourself.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone has the same 24 hours in a day. Most people who work coming out of school will spend 8 to 12 of those hours working and 8 or so of those hours sleeping. That means you have 4 hours every day for yourself. Those are the hours that separate you from others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leveraging yourself is doing things that multiply the amount of output you can do. Coding is an obvious example of this. It allows you to teach a machine to do what you want and automate repeated tasks. Writing online is another high-leverage activity. Writing online has allowed me to reconnect with people I’ve worked with in the past and engage in dialogue about content I consume and create.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compounding yourself means doing things that reap dividends in the future. Watching TV or a night of partying might be great in the moment, but provide little expected value in the future. Learning a new skill, having deep conversations with others, or reading books and blog posts are all examples of compounding activities that benefit you now and even more in the long term.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You won’t see the compounding benefits until an indeterminate amount of time later, just as you don’t really feel the benefits of your compounding monetary investments. But it’s important to never stop learning. Unlike school, those 4 hours a day you have to grow are unstructured. No one is telling you what books to read, what classes to take, or what projects to work on. Just do what’s interesting at first and build up the right habits. Then you’ll transition to more challenging things and discover more interests. If you don’t know what’s interesting to you, find others who do interesting things, which leads to my next point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr class=&quot;post-hr&quot; /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;surround-yourself-with-people-you-aspire-to-be-like-both-online-and-in-reality&quot;&gt;Surround yourself with people you aspire to be like, both online and in reality.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The people you aspire to be like got there for a reason. The internet allows you to bring these people to your sphere of consciousness. Leverage the internet to connect with inspirational individuals online. Twitter is one of the best ways to do this. David Perell, Benedict Evans, Ben Thompson, Naval Ravikant, and Nassim Taleb are some of my favorite follows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The purpose of following these people is not to constantly think “Why am I not like so and so and he’s only 23 years old too?”. It’s so you’re constantly thinking “What can I do differently that so and so is doing?”. The more you surround yourself with people that you aspire to be like, the more you can filter out the signal from the noise, and figure out what works for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now back to reality. Maintain the relationships you made through college. My trick is to keep one common thread  that ties you together with another person. Common ones for me are working out, working on a project, or investments. These relationships are essential to having candid conversation and exposing yourself to different life perspectives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been fortunate to live with my close friend &lt;a href=&quot;https://nickchua.me&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Nick&lt;/a&gt; as it’s sparked conversations about a lot of crazy ideas, challenged each of us to develop our blogs and newsletter, and kept us accountable with our health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr class=&quot;post-hr&quot; /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;savor-your-20s&quot;&gt;Savor your 20s.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Gentlemen, up until the age of 25, people will forgive your mistakes and believe in your potential &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;25-30, this drops off, you’re lucky if your parents still “believe in you” &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;30+, you’re a ghost, and no cares about you. You’re on your own entirely &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Don’t waste your 20s&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Alexander J.A Cortes (@AJA_Cortes) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/AJA_Cortes/status/1150983656506159105?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;July 16, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I couldn’t stop thinking about this tweet after I read it. While this tweet isn’t entirely true in my opinion, there definitely is something uniquely powerful about being a young college graduate in their 20s. You can ask questions and not know something and it’s completely ok. People make time for you because they’re invested in your growth potential. You can work on ideas others think are completely crazy. Being a young college graduate in their 20s is an asset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nassim Taleb always talks about identifying the undervalued assets in society. In my opinion, the fact there is high forgiveness for failure in your early 20s is undervalued. Most people come out of top schools and get a cushy, well-paying job - a fairly low risk proposition - as I did. Savoring my early 20s is grabbing onto more risk. I’m excited to see what challenges this next year will bring.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Reflections from a year of working. Taking care of yourself, leveraging and compounding yourself, and surrounding yourself with interesting people online and offline. Most importantly, taking risks at a young age.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:5000/images/berkeley-sunset.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Cities from First Principles</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:5000/city" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cities from First Principles" /><published>2019-07-11T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-07-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:5000/city</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:5000/city">&lt;p&gt;I spent the first 18 years of my life in the suburbs of the South Bay Area. I took the bus once, occasionally took the Caltrain up the Peninsula, and didn’t take the BART until I moved to Berkeley for college. It wasn’t until I went on a family vacation to Hong Kong did I experience a modern city, and I’ve been hooked ever since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The density of people, the diversity in coffeeshops and restaurants, and the towering architecture make cities feel alive in such a unique way. My favorite activity when traveling, or even while living in a city, is just exploring different parts of the city and observing the people and architecture. Through all my travels, I’ve become increasingly curious about why cities are the way they are today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I discovered Edward Glaeser’s &lt;em&gt;Triumph of the City&lt;/em&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;https://devonzuegel.com/post/cities-reading-list&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Devon Zuegel’s cities reading list&lt;/a&gt;, and it was a great read for foundational knowledge on the history of cities and the elements of successful cities. In this post, I compile the knowledge from the book and my own experiences to define my two first principles of successful cities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr class=&quot;post-hr&quot; /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-designed-for-people&quot;&gt;1. Designed for people&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you think about a city, some examples that come to mind are New York, Hong Kong, or Singapore. Dense, bustling, and alive. It’s awesome to be a person moving through these cities. Walk 20 feet and you see a new set of coffee shops, bars, restaurants, and shops. Hop on a train and it takes you to a whole different neighborhood with its own unique culture. These are cities designed for people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It sucks being a car in these cities. Tight roads, congestion, and pedestrians jaywalking out of nowhere. In my opinion, that’s a good thing. Cars should be the last resort to get around a city. Cities are made for people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s take compare cities designed for cars and cities designed for people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/vietnam-cars.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive img-half&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/sunnyvale-cars.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive img-half&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The left image is Ho Chi Minh city in Vietnam. Wide roads filled with cars and motorcycles encroach pedestrians trying to cross the street. There are some high-rises, but they are generally single-use buildings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The right image is Sunnyvale. This might be the densest part of the South Bay Area, yet it’s still built for cars. Wide roads and wide buildings. It’s not a very interesting place to walk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a side note, it was way harder for me to find pictures of cities designed for people, which I think shows how uninteresting these types of places can be. With that in in mind, let’s take a look at cities designed for people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/chicago-people.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive img-half&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/ny-people.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive img-half&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The left photo is Lincoln Park taken from an elevated train platform. It looks similar to the photo of downtown Sunnyvale, but we see more dense, mixed-use buildings, smaller roads with clear bike lanes, and nice tree-lined streets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the right is the Midtown West neighborhood of New York. Small shops and bike lanes line narrow streets. Buildings are taller than Lincoln Park and are mixed use as well. It’s an exciting place to walk around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cities designed for people are built for people scale. People like looking at new stores, restaurants, and coffeeshops every 15 feet. Cities are stimulating and different because of their density. You only get this by building up and not out, and zoning mixed-use commercial and residential buildings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some interesting statistics to close out this first part. Humans need 9 square feet of space where are cars take up between 300 and 400 square feet. The typical parking spot is about 120 square feet. That’s about double the size of the typical office cubicle. By building a city for cars, you by default make it unappealing to walk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Build cities for people. They’re more interesting and stimulating. They encourage people to walk, ride a bike, or take a train. But most importantly, bring people together and empower them to live more efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr class=&quot;post-hr&quot; /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-empowering-people&quot;&gt;2. Empowering people&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We talked a lot about structure and design in the previous section, but the most important part of a city is the people and empowering them to live better. Young college graduates flock to either New York or San Francisco because that’s where everyone is. It’s the network effect of cities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cities bring people and ideas together. Ideas spread randomly when you run into peers in coffeeshops or taking the subway. Successful cities like New York and San Francisco invest in the people. They focus on education and industries that compound the skills of its people, like technology and finance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why cities in the Rust Belt like Detroit struggled to survive. Assembly line manufacturing was low skill and not mentally stimulating. It was a knowledge destroying paradigm. They invested in large factories that were more suited for suburbs. They created jobs that didn’t attract the brightest individuals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bringing people together creates an abundance of opportunity. From finding a new job to starting a business  to rising up the corporate ladder, cities are at the core of all those professional interactions. There is also opportunity in meeting a mate. Among couples where both had a college degree, 50% are located in a city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cities also empower people to live greener. Homes and cars account for about 40% of household carbon output, and cities help reduce carbon emissions from both sources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/bikes.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive img-half&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/trainstation.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive img-half&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People travel less miles to get to their destination. Cities are connected via foot, bike or train. The average subway trip emits 0.9 pounds of carbon on average, while the average car trip emits 9 pounds of carbon. Less driving, smaller carbon footprint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Urban housing is generally smaller. Smaller homes take less heat or air conditioning. The average suburban house consumes 27% more electricity than the average urban household.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jobs, relationships, and the environment. Cities empower us to live more efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr class=&quot;post-hr&quot; /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you enjoyed my first post about cities. I’ve been fascinated by cities for awhile and finally started doing my own reading to learn more. I’ll be writing more posts on cities soon, and these two principles will be foundational concepts in future posts.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Inspired from *Triumph of the City*, my first principle of how to design a city: designed for people and empowering them. Some thoughts from my experiences living in the suburbs of the Bay Area and contrasting that with big cities like Chicago and New York.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:5000/images/nyskyline.jpg" /></entry></feed>